<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on superterran</title><link>https://superterran.github.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on superterran</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 19:58:40 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superterran.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>In Defense of GNOME 3.32</title><link>https://superterran.github.io/blog/2019-05-03-in-defense-of-gnome-3-32/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 19:58:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://superterran.github.io/blog/2019-05-03-in-defense-of-gnome-3-32/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s fair to say gnome-shell is, and always has been, polarizing. There&amp;rsquo;s folks like me who love it and think it&amp;rsquo;s picked up Apple&amp;rsquo;s mantle of driving the workstation desktop. There are others who see it as a spartan waste of good screen real estate. These two perspectives are at odds, and the GNOME community has gained a reputation for dismissing the latter and shoving the former down everyone&amp;rsquo;s throats. If you spend a few minutes appreciating the GNOME design philosophy or flipping through their Human Interface Guidelines, they are on on the right track here.</description></item><item><title>Crostini, GPU Acceleration and Steam</title><link>https://superterran.github.io/blog/2019-04-12-crostini-gpu-acceleration-and-steam/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 19:58:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://superterran.github.io/blog/2019-04-12-crostini-gpu-acceleration-and-steam/</guid><description>With ChromeOS 75 hitting the dev channel, we&amp;rsquo;re starting to see budding 3D support on the Pixel Slate. It&amp;rsquo;s still unstable, and not a lot works with it, but it may be worth playing around with if you&amp;rsquo;re interested in gaming on this great little tablet.
A small primer, ChromeOS has it&amp;rsquo;s own developer shell that you can access by typing Ctrl+Alt+T. This opens in a new tab.
If you install Crostini, the Linux subsystem, you should have a command called vmc.</description></item><item><title>Star Trek: Discovery, A Bitter Analysis</title><link>https://superterran.github.io/blog/2019-04-12-star-trek-discovery-a-bitter-analysis/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 19:58:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://superterran.github.io/blog/2019-04-12-star-trek-discovery-a-bitter-analysis/</guid><description>One thing I&amp;rsquo;ve learned this year is that I&amp;rsquo;m a toxic Star Trek fan. According to Shit Posters, both the Facebook group and Reddit commentor variety, I endlessly critique bothersome details and in doing so miss out on all the wonder and spectacle. Perhaps my adulation of TNG era Trek, knowing all the tapes and my reverence to all mighty Canon has poisoned me? Am I incapable of enjoying new Trek?</description></item><item><title>Living with A Pixel Slate</title><link>https://superterran.github.io/blog/2019-04-06-living-with-a-pixel-slate/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 19:58:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://superterran.github.io/blog/2019-04-06-living-with-a-pixel-slate/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve owned many tablets. My first tablet ran Windows 7 and was absymal. I recall my first Android tablet running Honeycomb, which didn&amp;rsquo;t really spark joy, as they say. The first tablet I ever liked was a Surface Pro 4, but I spilled some water on it and killed it. My last tablet, a Samsung TabPro running Windows 10 was my running favorite; it was the best of the Surface, but with USB-C and a thinner, lighter build.</description></item><item><title>Cool Uses for a Raspberry Pi</title><link>https://superterran.github.io/blog/2017-10-29-cool-uses-for-a-pi/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 19:58:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://superterran.github.io/blog/2017-10-29-cool-uses-for-a-pi/</guid><description>So this year I bought a 3D printed tiny Super Nintendo Case and put a Raspberry Pi 3 in it. At first, my only concern was to have a RetroPie setup, because of my childhood love of legally obtained ROMs. This part was easy enough and obtainable in one sitting. Putting a RetroPie together is quick and easy, and those guys have really done a great job bridging the gap between a terminal driven configuration and controller-only input.</description></item><item><title>Multitouch and Gnome</title><link>https://superterran.github.io/blog/2017-01-22-defending-gnome/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 19:58:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://superterran.github.io/blog/2017-01-22-defending-gnome/</guid><description>I find myself defending Gnome Shell far more than I&amp;rsquo;d ever thought warrented. It&amp;rsquo;s never from Unity fans - those guys associate linux with purple terminals and see Gnome as some fancy alternative they don&amp;rsquo;t know how to install. Every once in a while an xmonad user will shit all over the mouse driven DE and thise pompous need for cascading windows, but those guys generally know they represent the evil hacker lot.</description></item><item><title>Dell XPS 15 9550 Fedora Guide</title><link>https://superterran.github.io/blog/2016-04-17-dell_xps_15_9550/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 19:58:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://superterran.github.io/blog/2016-04-17-dell_xps_15_9550/</guid><description>I wanted to put together a little walk through to get the new Dell XPS 15 9550 laptop working well in Linux. I&amp;rsquo;ve been very happy with it so far, but I had to put in a few nights of research to really get it working as I want.
All instructions are for Fedora 23
##Provisioning
You can get this to work with UEFI, but I ended up going Legacy boot since I was having problems getting standby and hibernate to work when booting through EFI.</description></item><item><title>Linux on Dell XPS 15</title><link>https://superterran.github.io/blog/2016-04-13-dell-xps-15-linux/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2016 19:58:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://superterran.github.io/blog/2016-04-13-dell-xps-15-linux/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m blessed with a job that&amp;rsquo;s actively looking to step up their hardware game. So after a few nights of googling, I went to our IT guy and I was able to pursuade him to order the new Dell XPS 15 Non-touch 9550 P56F. My model has a Intel Core i7-6700HQ with 16GB of DDR4 RAM and a 512gb SSD on a PCI-e bus. Sickeningly awesome system. It hangs with my MBP but I still miss the trackpad.</description></item><item><title>HDMI CEC > Xbox One</title><link>https://superterran.github.io/blog/2016-04-02-hdmi-cec-better-than-xbox-one/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2016 19:58:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://superterran.github.io/blog/2016-04-02-hdmi-cec-better-than-xbox-one/</guid><description>I recently bought a TV with HDMI-CEC support, which could be one of the coolest features introduced to displays in a long long time. It&amp;rsquo;s kinda like IR over HDMI. It allows the TV to auto-switch sources, turn on and off, all depending on what you&amp;rsquo;re doing with the devices connected to it. The Chromecast turns on the display and switches input when you try and stream to it. My Steam Link will switch TV inputs and take control when I press the Steam button on the controller.</description></item><item><title>Looking for a good Linux Laptop</title><link>https://superterran.github.io/blog/2016-04-02-looking-for-a-good-linux-laptop/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2016 19:58:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://superterran.github.io/blog/2016-04-02-looking-for-a-good-linux-laptop/</guid><description>For years, I&amp;rsquo;ve ran some flavor of Linux on all my hardware. Lately, however, I awoke to discover that I&amp;rsquo;ve inadvertently factored out all my Linux boxes. It was innocuous enough. I&amp;rsquo;ve lent out my Linux desktop to a friend in need, and have mostly replaced it with a Microsoft Surface running Windows 10 and my newly acquired work laptop. My desktop at work was a bit of an anchor to a desk I no longer wanted, and so I traded in my two monitor Fedora box for a shiny new Macbook Pro.</description></item><item><title>Meld on OS X</title><link>https://superterran.github.io/blog/2016-01-12-meld-on-osx/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 19:58:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://superterran.github.io/blog/2016-01-12-meld-on-osx/</guid><description>Finding a good (free) diff tool is hard for OS X. Here, we&amp;rsquo;ll setup Meld (a popular diff tool on linux) to run with OS X and git.
First, install a decent Mac build of Meld, there&amp;rsquo;s a few options but here&amp;rsquo;s one I really like:
https://github.com/yousseb/meld/releases/tag/osx-v1
Once this is installed, you need to make bash script so Meld is command-line executable and can be invoke through git. Name this file &amp;lsquo;meld&amp;rsquo; and place it in a sourced directory that you can run commands from globally.</description></item><item><title>Chromcast Audio to PC Line-in as Multi-room Solution</title><link>https://superterran.github.io/blog/2016-01-10-my-chromecast-audio-setup/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 19:58:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://superterran.github.io/blog/2016-01-10-my-chromecast-audio-setup/</guid><description>Ever since I&amp;rsquo;ve moved into a bigger apartment I&amp;rsquo;ve lusted over a multi-room speaker setup so we can play audio everywhere in the house. Google&amp;rsquo;s new Chromecast Audio gives me the makings of this, with the recent update it lets you place Chromecasts in a &amp;lsquo;group&amp;rsquo; where they all play simutaniously. In my house, I made such a group and named it &amp;lsquo;Everwhere&amp;rsquo;. You can play Youtube or Spotify to &amp;lsquo;everywhere&amp;rsquo; and in every room it starts playing (pretty much) in sync.</description></item><item><title>Logitech MX Master and Linux</title><link>https://superterran.github.io/blog/2016-01-02-logitech-mx-master-and-linux/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 19:58:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://superterran.github.io/blog/2016-01-02-logitech-mx-master-and-linux/</guid><description>Logitech&amp;rsquo;s MX Master is perhaps one of the best mice available at the moment. Supporting both Bluetooth and the Unifying Receiver, loads of buttons, a vertical scroll wheel and micro-usb rechargable battery, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to go wrong with this thing. Unfortunately, the default key mappings on my linux desktop (Gnome 3) are terrible. The thumb button doesn&amp;rsquo;t do anything, and the vertical scroll does god knows what.
The vertical scroll button is a little harder to configure.</description></item></channel></rss>